<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>JINS KADWOOD</title>
    <link href="https://jinskadwood.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://jinskadwood.com" />
    <updated>2024-03-18T10:30:44+11:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Jins</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://jinskadwood.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>CONSULTING</title>
        <author>
            <name>Jins</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://jinskadwood.com/consulting.html"/>
        <id>https://jinskadwood.com/consulting.html</id>

        <updated>2024-02-23T16:53:45+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    As an experienced CTO, I know how challenging yet exhilarating the business&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>As an experienced CTO, I know how challenging yet exhilarating the business journey can be. The long nights coding, the race to launch, the talent hunts - I've been there! <br><br>Now I'm offering my insider expertise to founders &amp; businesses through tailored one-on-one consultations. If you're blocked by a technical roadblock or need an expert review of your systems and code, I can provide skilled guidance and advice.<br><br>Here's how it works:<br><br>First, send me an overview of your top concerns and questions. I'll review your needs and customize a 1-hour consultation plan to address them.<br><br>After an initial discussion, we'll sign an NDA for privacy then I'll conduct an in-depth examination of your team, processes, infrastructure, workflows and codebase. I want a comprehensive view of your startup's technical position. <br><br>I'll then summarize my findings and recommendations in a follow-up session. If beneficial, I'm happy to continue assisting your startup with my know-how. <br><br>My goal is to share hard-won insights that empower your success. Areas I can provide strategic counsel in include:<br><br>- Tackling technical debt <br>- Scaling engineering teams<br>- Boosting development velocity<br>- Structuring effective processes  <br>- Crafting product roadmaps<br>- Securing systems and data<br>- Mentoring your technical talent<br>- Managing vendor relationships <br>- And more!<br><br>With over a decade of experience building and advising startups, I've encountered most common pitfalls. Whether you need advice on how to improve performance, insight into best practices, or just a seasoned second opinion - let's talk.<br><br>My commitment is to provide honest, pragmatic and actionable guidance that allows your startup to reach new heights. Reach out if you need a technical mastermind in your corner!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>FRACTIONAL CTO</title>
        <author>
            <name>Jins</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://jinskadwood.com/fractional-cto.html"/>
        <id>https://jinskadwood.com/fractional-cto.html</id>

        <updated>2024-02-19T09:29:42+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Turning your big idea into a real product takes vision, passion and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">Turning your big idea into a real product takes vision, passion and know-how. You’ve got the vision covered, but bringing the right technical expertise and leadership onboard can be tricky. That’s where an Aussie tech expert like myself can help steer your product from concept to creation.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">As a Fractional CTO, I partner with savvy founders and provide the strategic technical guidance needed to build, launch and scale winning products efficiently. With over a decade's experience leading development at fast-growing startups, I bring battle-hardened skills to the table.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">Rather than charge an arm and a leg, I offer my services on a flexible, part-time basis. This makes top-notch technical leadership accessible for smart founders on a budget.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">Here’s how I can inject tech magic into your startup as your Fractional CTO:</p>
<h2 class="whitespace-pre-wrap"><strong>Initial Consultation - Let's chat about your big idea!</strong></h2>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">I'll meet with you for an in-depth discussion to learn more about your product vision, business goals, target market, timeline and budget. This consultation allows me to fully understand your objectives and constraints so I can tailor my CTO services to your specific needs. We'll dig into your tech requirements, explore potential solutions, and address any early concerns. I'll provide tailored advice on the best path forward.</p>
<h2 class="whitespace-pre-wrap"><strong>Development Review &amp; Audit - Let's inspect what you've built so far</strong></h2>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">Once onboard, I'll thoroughly assess your current tech stack, architecture, workflows and codebase to identify any gaps, risks or issues. This involves hands-on code reviews, product demos, discussions with your team, and analysis of your documentation. I can provide an objective outside perspective on what's working well and where there's room for improvement. My findings will be summarised in a detailed audit report.</p>
<h2 class="whitespace-pre-wrap"><strong>Corrective Action Plan - Let's upgrade development practices for optimal delivery</strong></h2>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">If any pressing issues emerge from the audit, such as substandard code quality, misalignment with product requirements, or flawed architectures, I'll work closely with you and your developers to address these promptly. This may involve rewriting portions of code, restructuring workflows, implementing testing, refactoring databases or other solutions. I'll draw up a corrective action plan tailored to your needs.</p>
<h2 class="whitespace-pre-wrap"><strong>Ongoing Communication Management - Let me be your tech translator</strong></h2>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">All interactions between you and developers will flow through me. I'll facilitate all requirements gathering, planning discussions, status updates, and other communications. This ensures your product vision is conveyed correctly to the team and no details are lost in translation. It also enables me to catch any misalignment early.</p>
<h2 class="whitespace-pre-wrap"><strong>Significant Cost Savings - Let me optimise your development spend</strong></h2>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">With my oversight, your product will be built faster, cheaper and better aligned to your commercial goals. As an experienced CTO, I can prevent unnecessary work, double-handling, scope creep, and other inefficiencies. I'll also keep your team focused on high-value tasks that move the needle. Conscientious management of development resources can result in considerable savings.</p>
<h2 class="whitespace-pre-wrap"><strong>Strategic Leadership - Let me be your startup's tech visionary</strong></h2>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">I’ll work closely with you to map out a technology roadmap tailored to your commercial objectives and user needs. As your Fractional CTO, I'll continuously evaluate emerging technologies and advise you on how these can be leveraged to give you a competitive edge. I'll also foster a culture of innovation and quality amongst your developers.</p>
<h2 class="whitespace-pre-wrap"><strong>Knowledge Transfer - Let me help build your in-house capabilities</strong></h2>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">If the end goal is to bring technical leadership fully in-house, I'm happy to coach and upskill a capable developer on your team to take on the CTO role long-term. We can also document processes, guidelines and other IP to embed our way of working within your startup's culture.</p>
<h2 class="whitespace-pre-wrap"><strong>Ongoing Support - Let me be your trusted tech advisor</strong></h2>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">I can continue providing ongoing CTO support at a fractional level even after we implemented all recommended improvements and processes. This ensures you still benefit from my expertise and advice as challenges emerge while pursuing product-market fit and scaling.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">Interested in leveraging my decade of experience to fast-track your product success? Let's grab a coffee and chat about how I can inject tech magic into your startup! I'm confident I can guide your product from concept to launch and beyond.</p>
<h2 class="whitespace-pre-wrap"><strong>Unleash the Power of Data - Let me be your Fractional Chief Data Officer</strong></h2>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">In addition to technical leadership, I can also help you tap into the power of data to gain key insights and competitive advantage.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">As your Fractional Chief Data Officer, I'll develop a tailored data strategy aligned with your business goals. This includes architecting the data pipelines, analytics systems and models required to get the right data in the right shape at the right time.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">My goal is to make your whole organization data-driven. I'll build self-serve dashboards and analytics tools that make data accessible to non-technical teams. This empowers your sales, marketing and product teams to gain data-backed insights and make smarter decisions.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">For your core product, I can design and develop analytics features that uncover compelling insights from your user data. These could provide a 360-degree view of your customers, reveal trends and patterns in usage, forecast churn risk or other critical metrics.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">I leverage best-of-breed data technologies like Spark, Kafka, Airflow, Snowflake, Looker, dbt and more to create robust analytics foundations. My data platforms are engineered for scale, enabling you to easily expand analytics capabilities as your product and data volumes grow.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">If generating value from your data is a priority, let's explore how my skills as a Fractional Chief Data Officer can fast-track your analytics success. I'm ready to help you become truly data-driven.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title> ♚</title>
        <author>
            <name>Jins</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://jinskadwood.com/homepage.html"/>
        <id>https://jinskadwood.com/homepage.html</id>

        <updated>2024-03-18T10:30:44+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Hi there, I'm Jins. I'm technologist, a startup enthusiast, product engineer, and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <figure class="post__image post__image--wide"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://jinskadwood.com/media/posts/1/IMG_8056.jpg" alt="" width="1182" height="1971" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://jinskadwood.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_8056-xs.jpg 300w ,https://jinskadwood.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_8056-sm.jpg 480w ,https://jinskadwood.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_8056-md.jpg 768w ,https://jinskadwood.com/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_8056-lg.jpg 1024w"></figure>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">Hi there, I'm Jins.</p>
<p>I'm technologist, a startup enthusiast, product engineer, and predictive leadership expert based in Sydney. With 20 years of experience launching digital ventures, growing revenue, and guiding founders, I've discovered the key to success lies in understanding the brain's predictive powers.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">Just as our minds constantly anticipate the future, I help businesses and teams predict and shape their path to growth. By cultivating positive expectations, navigating emotional landscapes, and harnessing the power of foresight, I enable startups and organisations to achieve extraordinary results.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">Whether you're a founder seeking technical guidance or a team in need of transformative leadership, I'm here to help you master the art of predictive success. Together, we'll turn your brilliant ideas into thriving realities and unlock your full potential.</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">Ready to embark on a journey of innovation and growth? Let's connect and explore how predictive leadership can take your venture to new heights! 🚀</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.jinskadwood.com/cto">READ SOME OF MY RECENT CONTENT</a></p>
<h3>SERVICES I CAN PROVIDE YOU</h3>
<h4 class="whitespace-pre-wrap"><strong>ONE-ON-ONE CONSULTATION</strong></h4>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">Not sure where to begin with your product? Book a 1-hour consultation and I'll provide tailored advice to kickstart your idea. We'll dive into your concept, tech needs, and early roadblocks. I'm happy to offer the first session free of charge - just cover my coffee :)</p>
<p><a href="https://jinskadwood.com/consulting.html">READ MORE ABOUT CONSULTATION</a></p>
<h4 class="whitespace-pre-wrap"><strong>FRACTIONAL CTO</strong></h4>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">Once you're ready to start building, I can join as your Fractional CTO. We'll start with an intensive workshop to review your tech stack, team, and processes. Then I'll work closely with your developers to deliver a solid product while optimizing workflows. My goal is to get your MVP launched quickly and cost-effectively!</p>
<p class="whitespace-pre-wrap">I'm passionate about collaborating with driven founders. If you're ready to turn your big idea into reality, get in touch! Let's build something awesome.</p>
<p><a href="https://jinskadwood.com/fractional-cto.html">READ MORE ABOUT FRACTIONAL CTO</a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
